Guide to the Bob Shultz Political Americana collection, circa 1960-2016
Shultz, Bob Political Americana collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bob Shultz Political Americana collection, circa 1960-2016
8566
Robert, Schultz, 1951-
Circa 23 cubic feet.
Ephemera, posters, printed material, toys, dishes, textiles, and buttons.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection consists of approximately 3,912 items, including buttons, ribbons, posters, bumper stickers, pamphlets, flyers, and other ephemera, and 3-dimensional items such as glassware, soap, cigars, clocks, figurines, toys, and more. Politcal items include all the major presidental candiates from the 1960s through the 2016 election as well as many smaller state and local campaigns, mainly from New York State.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert (Bob) D. Schultz received is BA (1977) and his MBA (1978) from Cornell University. He spent 25 years collecting political campaign memorabilia, primarily from the early 1960s onward. He donated his collection to Cornell University Library in 2016.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection consists of approximately 3,912 items, including buttons, ribbons, posters, bumper stickers, pamphlets, flyers, and other ephemera, and 3-dimensional items such as glassware, soap, cigars, clocks, figurines, toys, and more. Politcal items include all the major presidental candiates from the 1960s through the 2016 election as well as many smaller state and local campaigns, mainly from New York State.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schultz, Robert, 1951-; Reagan, Ronald; Bush, George, 1924-; Bush, George W. (George Walker), 1946-; Obama, Barack; Clinton, Hillary Rodham; Kerry, John; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; McCain, John; Romney, Mitt; Gore, Al, 1948-; Nixon, Richard; Kennedy, John F.; Ford, Gerald; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Kennedy, Edward; Kennedy, Robert; McGovern, John; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-
Subjects:
Campaign paraphernalia.; Elections.; Political campaigns.; Politicians.; Presidents -- Election.; Voting.
Places:
United States -- History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Ephemera.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Toys and other large election ephemera
Series II. Pins and buttons
Series III. Paper ephemera
Series IV. Oversized posters and flyers
Series V. Media
CONTAINER LIST
- Toys and other large election ephemera
  - Toys - George W. Bush, John Kerry, Hilary and Bill Clinton, 1992-2004 (Box 1)
  - Toy and dolls from various elections, Date Unknown (Box 2)
  - Dolls and collectibles related to Saddam Hussein, George Bush and Bill Clinton, 1990-2000 (Box 3)
  - Hats, glasses, pillow from various elections, 1994-2012 (Box 4)
  - Toys - George W. Bush, John Kerry, Hillary and Bill Clinton, 2007-2016 (Box 5)
  - Slippers - Reagan and George H.W. Bush, 1988-1992 (Box 6)
  - Toys - Regan, George H. W. Bush, and Bill Clinton, 1980-2000 (Box 9)
  - Textiles and T-shirts, Date Unknown (Box 10)
  - Masks - Carter, Reagan, George W. Bush, and Bill Clinton, Date Unknown (Box 11)
  - Glasses, plates and other fragile items, Date Unknown (Box 12)
  - Fragile items, bookends, and busts, Date Unknown (Box 13)
  - Various items relating to Bill Clinton, Al Gore, George H.W. Bush and the 200th anniversary of the White House, 1988-2000 (Box 14)
  - Various items relating to Jimmy Carter, 1976-1980 (Box 15)
  - Various items relating to George W. Bush, Kerry, and McCain, 2000-2004 (Box 16)
  - Various items relating to Romney and Obama, 2012 (Box 17)
  - Hats and other small items from various elections, Date Unknown (Box 18)
  - Various items related to Clinton, 1992; Includes some items from other elections. (Box 19)
  - Matchbooks, tin plates and a Nixon shower head., Date Unknown (Box 20)
  - 911 Material, toys, Russian nesting dolls, hats, Clinton memorabilia, 1960-2016 (Box 33)
- Pins and buttons
  - Buttons, Date Unknown (Box 7)
  - Buttons, Date Unknown (Box 8)
  - Buttons, Date Unknown (Box 20)
  - Pins and Buttons, Date Unknown (Box 24)
  - Pins and Buttons, Date Unknown (Box 25)
  - Pins and buttons - New York and other state and local elections, 1972-2002 (Box 26)
  - Pins and buttons: Taft through Bill Clinton, Date Unknown (Box 29)
  - Political buttons, 1950-2016 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Political buttons, 1950-2016 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Political buttons, 1950-2016 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Political buttons, 1960-2016 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Political buttons, 1960-2016 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Paper ephemera
  - Presidential: F.D. Roosevelt through Ralph Nader, 1936-2000; Includes stickers and some campaign give aways such as pens and matchbooks (Box 26)
  - Presidential: John Kerry through Ben Carson, 2004-2016; Includes stickers and some campaign give aways such as pens and matchbooks (Box 27)
  - Presidential: John F. Kennedy through 2016 candidates, 1960-2016; Includes legal sized materials. (Box 29)
  - F.D.R., Eisenhower, and Varia, 1932-1952 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson material, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Kennedy Johnson Texas Democratic Campaign, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - George McGovern campaign material, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Carter, Alexander, campaign material, 1974-1977 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Gore, Kemp, Regan, campaign material, 1980-1988 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Dole, Bush, Tsongas, campaign material, 1992-1996 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Gore, Clinton, campaign material, 1992-2000 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Bill Clinton, My Life, 2004-07-07 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Hillary Clinton campaign material, 2016 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Donald Trump campaign material, 2016 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - First in the National Presidential Town Hall, 2016-01-22 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Reagan, Lazio campaign material, 1980-2000 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - New York and other state and local elections, 1952-2002; Includes state elections for individuals who would go on to be president such as John F. Kennedy and George W. Bush (Box 27)
  - New York and other state and local elections, 1994-2006 (Box 29)
  - Non-election related material, Date Unknown; Includes some republican committee items, drug prevention and Y2K material (Box 27)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. material, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Space Program Ad Council, 1989-10 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Child Abuse Ad Council, 1989-03 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - The Statue of Liberty - Ellis Islan Restoration Ad Council, 1989-10 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - United Way of America, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Bicentennial of the Constitution Ad Council, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - NPCP, Crime Prevention Ad Council, Summer 1989 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Ad Council Campaigns, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Ad Council Advertisement, 1985-1995 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Political Stickers, Undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Magazines, Date Unknown; Mainly related to Bill and Hilary Clinton. (Box 21)
  - Newpapers, books, and magazines, Date Unknown (Box 22)
  - Liberty magazine, 1930-05-10 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Magazines, newspapers, 1945-2017 (Box 34)
    Surrender of Japan, Moon Landing, Saddam Hussein, JFK, Clintons, Ossama Bin Laden, 911, Trump
  - Shopping bags and other giveaway bags, Date Unknown; Mainly paper, some fabric or plastic. (Box 23)
  - Political Bags, 1960-2017 (Box 35)
- Oversized posters and flyers
  - Presidential Races
    - Coolidge and Dawes broadside, Undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - John F. Kennedy, Robert Kennedy, Eisenhower, 1952-1968 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Electoral campaign posters, 1960 (Mapcase-folder 30)
    - Nixon and McGovern, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Nixon, 1973; Extra large poster (Mapcase-folder 10)
    - Edward Kennedy and Carter, 1976-1980 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Mondale and Reagan, 1980-1984 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    - George H.W. Bush and Gore, 1988; This Gore material is from when he ran for president in 1988 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Bill Clinton and Gore, 1992 (Mapcase-folder 2)
    - Bill Clinton, 1993 (Mapcase-folder 10)
    - George H.W. Bush, Perot, Bill Clinton, and Bob Dole, 1992-1996 (Mapcase-folder 3)
    - Clinton, George H.W. Bush, and Perot, 1992; Standing posters with removable numbers (Mapcase-folder 11)
    - Gore and George W. Bush, 2000 (Mapcase-folder 4)
    - Dodd, Thompson, Giuliani, McCain, Santorum, Obama, Hillary Clinton, Edwards, Kerry, 2004-2008 (Mapcase-folder 5)
    - Gingrich, Romney, Perry, Huntsman, Obama, 2012 (Mapcase-folder 6)
    - Hillary Clinton, Rubio, Rand Paul, 2016 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Clinton/Trump, 2016 (Mapcase-folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous political posters, Undated (Mapcase-folder 31)
    - Assorted campaign posters, 1960-2006 (Mapcase-folder 33)
  - Presidential Pennants
    - Nixon, John F. Kennedy, Robert Kennedy, Carter, and Reagan, 1960-1985 (Mapcase-folder 16)
  - State and Local
    - Bleakley, 1936 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 1960s elections, 1960-1969; Includes Edward Kennedy, Wallace, Goldwater, Reagan, Rockefeller, Javits (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 1970s elections, 1970-1979; Includes Moynihan, Ottinger, Goldberg, Tip O'Neill (Mapcase-folder 7)
    - 1980s elections, 1980-1989; Includes Edward Kennedy (Mapcase-folder 8)
    - Bill Clinton (Governor), 1982-1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1990s elections, 1990-1999; Includes George W. Bush, D'Amato, Dodd, Moynihan, Pataki, Cuomo (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 2000s elections, 2000-2009; Includes Cuomo, Spitzer, Hillary Clinton, Lazio (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Non-elections related
    - War and veteran themes, 1942-2008 (Mapcase-folder 12)
    - Patriotic and 9/11 themes, 2001-2002 (Mapcase-folder 13)
    - Public service announcements and Ad Council, 1980-1999 (Mapcase-folder 14)
    - Environment and forest fire themes, 1971-1989 (Mapcase-folder 15)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 18)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 19)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 20)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 21)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 22)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 23)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 24)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 25)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 26)
    - Ad Council advertising, Undated (Mapcase-folder 27)
    - Drugs, HIU, Cancer, Undated (Mapcase-folder 28)
    - It Touches Us All posters, 2001 (Mapcase-folder 32)
    - Budweiser God Bless America, 2000 (Mapcase-folder 34)
    - PSA and campaign posters, 1968-2001 (Mapcase-folder 35)
- Media
  - It Takes a Village by Antonio, 2000; CD-3449; CD with "Vote for Hillary" on the back cover (Box 28)
    - William Jefferson Clinton Presidential Center and Partk virtual tour, CD-3450 (Box 28)
    - My Life by Bill Clinton, 2004; CD-3451-3456; Book on CD read by Bill Clinton (Box 28)
    - Mario Cuomo - Keynote Session: Management, 1991; TR-11668 (Box 28)
    - The Three Great Debates of the 1960 Presidential Political Campaign, 1960; SR-15350-15352 (Box 28)
    - John F. Kennedy - The Presidential Years 1960-1963, 1963; SR-15353; Recordings of speeches given by Kennedy during his presidency (Box 28)
    - The First Family featuring Vaughn Meader, 1962; SR-15354; Comedic recording. (Box 28)
    - Wallace souvenir album, 1963; SR-15355 (Box 28)
    - The Wallace Stand, 1972; SR-15356 (Box 28)
    - The Man from Hope, 1996; V-9812 (Box 29)
      >Part of the Clinton/Gore campaign
    - Hillary, 2000; V-9813 (Box 29)
    - Team Hillary "Garbage", 2000-11-04; V-9814 (Box 29)
    - NY Times Clinton Book review, Undated; ZD-82 (Box 29)
    - Reclaiming America, a political profile of Robert F. Kennedy, 1 of 2, Undated; tr-16728 (Box 36)
      Audio cassette
    - Reclaiming America, a political profile of Robert F. Kennedy, 2 of 2, Undated; tr-16729 (Box 36)
    - Robert F. Kennedy, in his own words/Address to the DNC, 1964; tr-16730 (Box 36)
    - The toughest job in the world, Undated; tr-16731 (Box 36)
      Coalition for America's children
    - The toughest job in the world, Undated; V-10464-10465 (Box 36)
      Video cassette
    - Bob Schultz Cornell Club presentation, Undated; V-10466 (Box 36)
    - "What a Wonderful World", "America the Beautiful", 1989; SR-20851 (Box 36)
      Environmental Defense Fund
      45 rpm record